<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.amy-codes.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.amy-codes.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-07-17T16:05:01-05:00</updated><id>https://www.amy-codes.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">{amy-codes}</title><subtitle>A landing zone for blog posts, technical talks, and other nerdy ramblings.</subtitle><author><name>Amy Negrette</name></author><entry><title type="html">The COVID Post</title><link href="https://www.amy-codes.com/irl/2022/07/15/the-covid-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The COVID Post" /><published>2022-07-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-07-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.amy-codes.com/irl/2022/07/15/the-covid-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.amy-codes.com/irl/2022/07/15/the-covid-post.html"><![CDATA[<p>On June 7th, I was doing a product launch livestream. This was a huge event for me and one I’m still very proud of. I’ve been doing technical speaking and development on serverless architectures for a few years so the opportunity to join a cloud provider launching its first Functions as a Service product was a huge experience for me and one that was very much my jam. Months of prep work and I was at the start of a glut of activities. This livestream was just the first. Half-way through, I started to feel winded.</p>

<iframe width="600" height="338" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vmYayQC_0BU" title="DigitalOcean Functions Launch Livestream" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Of course, that part was natural. I’m asthmatic already and talking in ‘High Octane’ mode for an hour would be a lot. I had also taken an at-home test the day before and I was negative for COVID-19, so it must have been my allergies.</p>

<p>“It wasn’t,” says the narrator.</p>

<p>I had a minor asthma attack after the event during our post-show wrap-up where we thanked all of our guests. Again, I’m asthmatic, and that’s just a thing that happens sometimes.</p>

<p>I tested again, and I was <em>VERY POSITIVE</em>. You know you’re positive if the line is bright red before the control line shows up.</p>

<p>Did I mention I had three weeks of this promo to do?</p>

<p>I should mention how I got COVID. My parents went to a wedding for my anti-masker cousin’s daughter because Their Freedom, I guess. I’m not saying there was an outbreak, but my dad did get COVID as well as one of my aunts (and allegedly everyone and their tables). My parents are in their 70s, so they were kept separate and my husband was out of the country, which meant I was taking care of everyone. Then my oldest son, aged 9 years old, got it, missing the last days of school who immediately got quarantined with my dad. The night before my livestream, my 6 year old son got it.</p>

<p>You can take care of so many people and dodge so many bullets before one gets you.</p>

<p>Now back to where we are, where I got it. By this time, my dad and my 9 year old were already asymptomatic but still quarantined until they tested negative. Their symptoms was like a persistent flu. So was my 6 year old’s. So I thought maybe, just maybe, I had been worried for nothing.</p>

<p>I called my doctor. HA, HA no I didn’t, I sent her an e-mail. Because I’m incapable of judging the severity of my own health in an emergency.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I tested positive today for Covid. It’s an issue for me to breathe and I have to push air in and out to do so as if I’m having an asthmatic stress. Any advice would be appreciated, thank you!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Yes. That is how I described the shortness of breath. I was only positive for a few hours so far, and I was already under distress. But at the time, it was just the breathing. She sent me Paxlovid, some new miracle anti-viral that was approved only earlier that year. She signed off her part of the conversation with, “If this doesn’t work, <em>go to the ER immediately</em>.” You see, I have a reputation.</p>

<p><img src="paxlovid.jpg" alt="Paxlovid" /></p>

<p>I heard stories. A common symptom was the breathlessness. Multiple people saying, ‘It’s like an elephant sitting on your chest.’ Well, that’s how I am all the time. So I was terrified. Would I asphyxiate? Are they going to send me to the hospital because that shit’s expensive and I don’t wanna.</p>

<p>What I haven’t read was about the stabbing.</p>

<p>Oh? The stabbing, you ask? I didn’t asphyxiate. What did happen was my ribs turning into <em>knives</em>. Every breath felt like searing hot razor wire cutting into my flesh from the inside. Every cough was a stabbing pain between my shoulders. I had a dull, radiating pain in all of my joints. My fever during this peaked at 104.7 degrees Farenheit. I’ve been in the hospital for different things before but this was new and unwelcome.</p>

<p>But Paxlovid was a dang miracle. It’s a 5-day regiment with 3 pills in the morning and 3 pills in the evening. By Day 4, my fever was down to a ‘reasonable’ non-hospital worthy temperature in the high 101s and I could breathe without screaming. By Day 6, the fever had completely broken and I could stand up again.</p>

<p>By Day 8, I was mobile and Livestreaming again. Because this launch was huge for me. Watch the tape back and you can hardly notice.</p>

<iframe width="600" height="338" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iNwQqOs5HFc" title="Getting Started With DigitalOcean Functions" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Day 10, I tested negative. I was so happy. I got hit a little harder than the rest of my family, but we all survived only a little worse for wear.</p>

<p>Again, no.</p>

<p>Have you heard of Long COVID? Because it’s not what I thought it was! I thought it referred to Long Haulers, where you were hospitalized for longer than 3 weeks and ended up with life long respiratory issues.</p>

<p>That is not what it is. According to the CDC, “Some people who have been infected with the virus that causes COVID-19 can experience long-term effects from their infection, known as post-COVID conditions (PCC) or long COVID.”</p>

<p>Excuse me? <em>Any</em> post-COVID conditions?</p>

<p>I must have been excited before but I hadn’t noticed. But you know who did notice? Anyone who had to interact with me when I wasn’t ‘ON’. I suffered from severe fatigue which would lead to me just falling asleep at random points during the day regardless of how much rest I had the night before. The pain in my ribs only dulled. The brain fog was real. I’ve been pregnant twice, I know what brain fog is. It’s the body’s way of tricking a human body into forgetting the severe pain that is the birthing process by making you forget that shit ever happened. Post-COVID, I would either space out or black out completely. There would be blocks of time that were just gone. I also had a difficulty gauging time, but frankly I’ve been having problems with that since lockdown.</p>

<p>Another thing to be worried about, yay, which isn’t generalized anxiety when there’s literal things to be worried about all the time. They said long COVID could last anywhere between one to six months if not for the rest of your life.</p>

<p>Do you know how many chronic conditions I have right now? Enough that I don’t have the time to deal with this shit.</p>

<p>It didn’t last six months. I was lucky, it was only a month. It’s July 14th. It’s been several days since I’ve randomly passed out during the day. I’m in PT to help with the pain which is nearly gone. I’m <em>remembering things</em> and <em>knowing what time of day it is</em> like some sort of psychic.</p>

<p>That’s why I wrote this. I didn’t hear about experiences like mine, so I wanted this out there. Whenever someone I know got COVID, I’d ask if what they thought of the taste of Paxlovid, because there’s a lot of posts saying it’s the worst thing they’ve ever had to choke down. Personally, I’m sick often enough that it’s #3 in flavors I hate. Or how much like knives do their ribs feel? You know, looking for sympathy. But someone was ‘you know that’s for the most extreme cases.’ I DIDN’T UNTIL YOU TOLD ME. I am nothing, if not extreme, I guess.</p>

<p>I want people to know why I’m double-masked outside on a Summer’s day. Why I’m always paranoid about what I touch or who I’m with. Because this <em>sucked</em>.</p>

<p>I think, truly, that it’s done.</p>

<p>But if I get it again and I get hospitalized, someone’s gonna pay.</p>]]></content><author><name>Amy Negrette</name></author><category term="irl" /><category term="irl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On June 7th, I was doing a product launch livestream. This was a huge event for me and one I’m still very proud of. I’ve been doing technical speaking and development on serverless architectures for a few years so the opportunity to join a cloud provider launching its first Functions as a Service product was a huge experience for me and one that was very much my jam. Months of prep work and I was at the start of a glut of activities. This livestream was just the first. Half-way through, I started to feel winded.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introvert’s Guide to Tech Conferences</title><link href="https://www.amy-codes.com/blog/2022/04/09/conf-tips.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introvert’s Guide to Tech Conferences" /><published>2022-04-09T15:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-04-09T15:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.amy-codes.com/blog/2022/04/09/conf-tips</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.amy-codes.com/blog/2022/04/09/conf-tips.html"><![CDATA[<p>In the spring of 2019, I spoke at five events in three months including APItheDocs, AWS Summit, Revolution Conf, AWS Community Day, and PearConf, all differing in size and target audiences. During this time, I also participated in partner meetings on behalf of my company and had to go to a family funeral. Unfortunately, I have a moderate level of social anxiety which meant I simply did not have the internal bandwidth to handle all of these days Outside. 
Sometime between RevolutionConf and AWS Community Day, my body just gave in. I had the motivation but I barely had any energy to move around and handle my family’s needs, much less draft more slides.</p>

<p>This rigorous schedule did allow me to try out different things so that I could get the most out of any given event while still maintaining the boundaries I needed for myself.</p>

<p><img src="1.png" alt="Calendar" /></p>
<h2 id="check-a-calendar">Check a Calendar</h2>
<p>One of the issues I had this Spring was I submitted far and wide. Of course, it completely escaped me why they call it Conference Season, as in many happening at the same time. So I ended up withdrawing several submissions as others started to get accepted. I unfortunately did not realize that they would basically also fall one week after another after another. If you need more than a few days to rest, make sure you check the dates accordingly and withdraw when you need to.</p>

<p><img src="2.png" alt="Schedule" /></p>
<h2 id="recon-is-key">Recon is Key</h2>
<p>Large conferences will usually release maps prior to the event. Make sure to cover your needs prior to the event itself. Where are there bathrooms? Food? How many sessions can you effectively get to? If you need a break, where would you go? How do you get to and from the event? You don’t necessarily need to remember most of this, but it’s good to have it noted down somewhere for reference. Anything you can’t answer and feel you need answers about, absolutely contact the event organizers. They’re there to help you.</p>

<p>Also, especially true for <em>the times we live in</em>, confirm the local Covid-19 protocols for the event. Even if the city the event takes place in has lax rules as far as masks and vaccinations, the event venue or the event itself may have more strict rules all together. There may also be areas where one can take a mask break or sanitizer stations.</p>

<p><img src="3.png" alt="Gear" /></p>
<h2 id="check-your-gear">Check Your Gear</h2>
<p>I never go anywhere without a laptop, even when I’m not working. I’ve tried using a tablet but I need a keyboard in order to be effective. This naturally differs from person to person, but generally you should make sure whatever devices you do carry are charged (such as your phone), that you stay hydrated and fed, and that you bring anything that calms you down. Also deodorant, because conferences are crammed with people and smells rub off.</p>

<p>My checklist looks like this:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Laptop</li>
  <li>Laptop charger</li>
  <li>Phone</li>
  <li>Battery Pack</li>
  <li>Headphones</li>
  <li>HDMI-to-USB-C (During Speaking engagements only)</li>
  <li>Bottle of Water</li>
  <li>Protein Bar ( 1 bar per 2 hours )</li>
  <li>Mint Flavored Rolaids</li>
  <li>Deodorant</li>
  <li>Allergy Kit</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="4.png" alt="Let's Be Friends" /></p>
<h2 id="make-a-friend">Make a Friend</h2>
<p>I’m not good at socializing. I love it when people come up after talks so we can chat, but sometimes I have to run off due to a blood sugar crash or an anxiety attack. Thankfully, I’m on a handful of Tech Industry Slacks. To prevent myself from simply doing my talk and leaving, or burying myself in a corner of a breakout room for four hours, I set up a Conference Buddy ahead of time. I ask around to see who’s going to be at the event I’ll be at and meet up with them during a lunch or coffee break. This way I can meet people outside of work and get their take on how the event is going or if there’s a specific session I should go see.</p>

<p>Overall, this will make the events less daunting, as I’ve removed my well-known anxiety triggers out of the equation. So long as I give myself enough time to recuperate, I am able to get the most out of an event, even when it’s difficult for me to be there. Of course, the price of not giving yourself enough time is emotional exhaustion halfway through.</p>

<p><img src="5.png" alt="Make More Friends" /></p>
<h2 id="make-more-friends">Make More Friends!</h2>
<p>I meet a lot of people at these events, either through the Hallway Track, after my talks, or through friends of friends. In that moment, I remember no one. If remote life has taught me anything, it’s that I’ll only remember a person’s face if I see them weekly with their name directly under them. Barring that, on every slide is my twitter handle and sometimes my LinkedIn. This allows anyone at my talk to message me to say hi or reference my work.</p>

<p>But that’s one hour, maybe, out of the entire time I’m there. I also have contact cards as well as a discord people can add, allowing people to contact me however they feel is most convenient.</p>

<p>I hope these tips help you out! I know they’ll help me when I have to do it all again.</p>]]></content><author><name>Amy Negrette</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="update" /><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the spring of 2019, I spoke at five events in three months including APItheDocs, AWS Summit, Revolution Conf, AWS Community Day, and PearConf, all differing in size and target audiences. During this time, I also participated in partner meetings on behalf of my company and had to go to a family funeral. Unfortunately, I have a moderate level of social anxiety which meant I simply did not have the internal bandwidth to handle all of these days Outside. Sometime between RevolutionConf and AWS Community Day, my body just gave in. I had the motivation but I barely had any energy to move around and handle my family’s needs, much less draft more slides.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello, World!</title><link href="https://www.amy-codes.com/blog/2022/04/03/introductions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello, World!" /><published>2022-04-03T15:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-04-03T15:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.amy-codes.com/blog/2022/04/03/introductions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.amy-codes.com/blog/2022/04/03/introductions.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello! It’s me! I’m back and updating again. I’ll be honest, I don’t feel like giving a whole update on where I’ve been. Short version is that the Pandemic happened, is still happening, and it’s no different than everyone else. What is important however is that I had the opportunity to take stock of what frustrated me about my work and make a conscious decision to focus on the things I truly wanted to do. This is just a blurb, but I’ll get into it as tie goes on.</p>

<p>Still, it’s nice to see you! Feel free to message me, DM’s are open!</p>]]></content><author><name>Amy Negrette</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="update" /><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! It’s me! I’m back and updating again. I’ll be honest, I don’t feel like giving a whole update on where I’ve been. Short version is that the Pandemic happened, is still happening, and it’s no different than everyone else. What is important however is that I had the opportunity to take stock of what frustrated me about my work and make a conscious decision to focus on the things I truly wanted to do. This is just a blurb, but I’ll get into it as tie goes on.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fruits and Turnips: Cost Optimization in Animal Crossing</title><link href="https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2021/05/04/fruits-turnips.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fruits and Turnips: Cost Optimization in Animal Crossing" /><published>2021-05-04T15:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-04T15:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2021/05/04/fruits-turnips</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2021/05/04/fruits-turnips.html"><![CDATA[<p>Our priorities inform what we do with our money. What do you really need those bells for? Are you trying to add an extension on your home or get a five star island? How will what you buy help? How do you plan to get those bells?</p>

<p>One of the ways to make bells is the selling of fruits and turnips. Fruits are an abundant sellable resource that requires space on your island (infrastructure) and a friend’s island to sell (connections). The return rate is steady but not time blocked. Turnips appear once a week with ten selling windows a week that can vary wildly on price where taking a loss is pretty common.</p>

<p>Knowing this, I’ll demonstrate how spend can tell us what our priorities were and the pros and cons to each approach. Cost management is more than cutting costs, but making sure the costs that are made support those priorities.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IEOlbOt4yKk" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name>Amy Negrette</name></author><category term="talk" /><category term="update" /><category term="youtube" /><category term="talk" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our priorities inform what we do with our money. What do you really need those bells for? Are you trying to add an extension on your home or get a five star island? How will what you buy help? How do you plan to get those bells?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Best Frenemies: Lambda, Fargate, and Serverless Containers</title><link href="https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2020/06/11/lambda-fargate.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best Frenemies: Lambda, Fargate, and Serverless Containers" /><published>2020-06-11T15:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-06-11T15:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2020/06/11/lambda-fargate</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2020/06/11/lambda-fargate.html"><![CDATA[<p>This talk will go over the limits of FaaS, how to make container changes to its container, and if containerized solutions can actually fix this problem.</p>

<p>This talk was delivered at AWS Midwest Community Day.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7nKy7tjB-Ms" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name>Amy Negrette</name></author><category term="talk" /><category term="update" /><category term="youtube" /><category term="talk" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This talk will go over the limits of FaaS, how to make container changes to its container, and if containerized solutions can actually fix this problem.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Best Frenemies: Serverless Containers</title><link href="https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2020/03/22/serverless-containers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best Frenemies: Serverless Containers" /><published>2020-03-22T15:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-03-22T15:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2020/03/22/serverless-containers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2020/03/22/serverless-containers.html"><![CDATA[<p>This talk will go over the limits of FaaS, how to make container changes to its container, and if containerized solutions can actually fix this problem.</p>

<p>This talk was delivered at Container Camp in Sydney, Australia remotely.</p>

<iframe src="https://slides.com/amycodes/containercamp-serverlesscontainers/embed" width="576" height="420" title="ContainerCamp: Serverless Frenemies" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name>Amy Negrette</name></author><category term="talk" /><category term="update" /><category term="talk" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This talk will go over the limits of FaaS, how to make container changes to its container, and if containerized solutions can actually fix this problem.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Live your best Tech Conference</title><link href="https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2020/03/10/tech-conference.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Live your best Tech Conference" /><published>2020-03-10T15:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-03-10T15:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2020/03/10/tech-conference</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2020/03/10/tech-conference.html"><![CDATA[<p>This talk will give a quick walkthrough of how to make the most of any tech conference including how to prepare, what to look out for, and what to skip.</p>

<iframe src="https://slides.com/amycodes/conf-survival/embed" width="576" height="420" title="Live Your Best Tech Conference" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>This talk was delivered at DevTogether in Chicago, IL for ‘No Code Talks’ four days before Chicago went into lockdown.</p>]]></content><author><name>Amy Negrette</name></author><category term="talk" /><category term="update" /><category term="youtube" /><category term="talk" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This talk will give a quick walkthrough of how to make the most of any tech conference including how to prepare, what to look out for, and what to skip.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Manage your Serverless Servers</title><link href="https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2020/02/27/serverless-servers-sdn.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Manage your Serverless Servers" /><published>2020-02-27T14:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-02-27T14:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2020/02/27/serverless-servers-sdn</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2020/02/27/serverless-servers-sdn.html"><![CDATA[<p>The backbone of serverless architecture is using Functions as a Service to handle your logic needs. This is done by spinning up containers to run these functions on demand. For many use cases, this would be enough. Other times, you would need to manage small configurations such as time outs and memory. More often, a developer needs to use third-party libraries or a company built and maintained library. This talk will go over all of these options, how to choose which is the best for your particular use case, and how to implement them.</p>

<p>This talk was delivered at Serverless Days in Nashville, TN with content modified from ServerlessConf.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/81xlZYGOMc4" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name>Amy Negrette</name></author><category term="talk" /><category term="update" /><category term="youtube" /><category term="talk" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The backbone of serverless architecture is using Functions as a Service to handle your logic needs. This is done by spinning up containers to run these functions on demand. For many use cases, this would be enough. Other times, you would need to manage small configurations such as time outs and memory. More often, a developer needs to use third-party libraries or a company built and maintained library. This talk will go over all of these options, how to choose which is the best for your particular use case, and how to implement them.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">More than just Talk</title><link href="https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2019/12/07/more-than-talk.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="More than just Talk" /><published>2019-12-07T14:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-12-07T14:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2019/12/07/more-than-talk</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2019/12/07/more-than-talk.html"><![CDATA[<p>You’ve had your abstract accepted and now it’s time to do some work. What should be on your slides? How long should it take? How do you prepare? Answer all of that and more at Own your Expertise!</p>

<p>This presentation was delivered at Write/Speak/Code’s Own Your Expertise event in Chicago, IL.</p>

<iframe src="https://slides.com/amycodes/build-talk/embed" width="576" height="420" title="More than Just Talk" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name>Amy Negrette</name></author><category term="talk" /><category term="update" /><category term="talk" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’ve had your abstract accepted and now it’s time to do some work. What should be on your slides? How long should it take? How do you prepare? Answer all of that and more at Own your Expertise!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Legacy …and beyond!</title><link href="https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2019/11/07/legacy-beyond.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Legacy …and beyond!" /><published>2019-11-07T14:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-11-07T14:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2019/11/07/legacy-beyond</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.amy-codes.com/talk/2019/11/07/legacy-beyond.html"><![CDATA[<p>For traditional application engineers with a few years under their belt, technology trends come and go. It’s hard to get excited when you’ve lost time to trends that never got adopted while the industry tells you that your language is dead. This talk will identify the source of these Legacy Feelings and define which skills can be immediately applied to the next step of your career. You’ll learn how to course correct in a cost and time effective way, including finding low friction paths for upskilling, the actual price of learning new technologies, and your options for online education and communities. Legacy is more than old tech, it’s experience you can monetize and use to innovate your future.</p>]]></content><author><name>Amy Negrette</name></author><category term="talk" /><category term="update" /><category term="talk" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[For traditional application engineers with a few years under their belt, technology trends come and go. It’s hard to get excited when you’ve lost time to trends that never got adopted while the industry tells you that your language is dead. This talk will identify the source of these Legacy Feelings and define which skills can be immediately applied to the next step of your career. You’ll learn how to course correct in a cost and time effective way, including finding low friction paths for upskilling, the actual price of learning new technologies, and your options for online education and communities. Legacy is more than old tech, it’s experience you can monetize and use to innovate your future.]]></summary></entry></feed>